Hello everyone
Today we are going to play one more good old classic, FTB Ultimate
Which is also the pack where I first encountered GregTech
Anyways, we shall quickly get started with a new world
And we spawned close to a village that seems to not have any loot chests
After a quick peek at it
We get started and do the usual vanilla stuff
Meaning we rush a bed and then gather some materials
Now that we have a bed and some food
We can go gather some minerals
And that should be enough to get our base started
And the first thing we shall do is get some building materials
We are going to make our base with the good old trusty stone bricks
And after some work
Here we have our new shelter with a nice window on the sky
Now we can start processing the minerals with an old pulverizer
This is from before the introduction of Forge Energy
Back when we used Minecraft Joules
Now, before moving on with our factory
We shall get some proper tools
Such as a Power Armor
This armor doesn't even look cool in that version
And as we made it
It only provides a different cosmetic
To make it have any use
We need a Power Armor tinker table
That requires one emerald which we didn't find while mining
But luckily, villagers trades exist in that version
And that guy has a nice offer
We accept this quest from the guild hall
And quickly proceed to fill it
And thus we have our tinkers table to tweak our armor
Inside that we can see our armor equipped modules
And we can add, remove or edit them
The first thing we want is to add some plating so that it provides some Protection
We quickly craft the material required for the upgrade
And proceed into installing it into our armor
Next, we can choose how thick we want our plating to be
The more thick the more protection we gain
But we also have more weight to carry around
Since we want to be well-protected
We install it at maximum defense on each part of our armor
And thus we have an unbreakable armor as good as a diamond one but made out of iron
The issue is that it's heavy
To workaround that
We can install some augmentations on our leggings to help us walk with all of that weight
And again, we can tweak how powerful and in what way these augmentations shall help us walk
However, these require power
So we also have to install a battery
Which is going to increase further up our weight
And of course, we need some generators to charge up our batteries
However, all of the generators we can embed in our armor require control circuits
Which require glowstone
Before going into the nether
We craft a power tool
Which will make any other tool obsolete
Freeing a lot of hotbar space
This robotic arm can do about everything you could need
Such as the basic mining tools
To get the obsidian
We can upgrade it with some diamonds
And we should probably overclock the pick feature at the maximum for that task
And thus we can now punch obsidian with our bare robotic hands
Before going into the nether, we should get some more cool features
Such as a rail gun
Or maybe we can get that later on
For the moment let's make a melee assistant be enough
Then we fully charge our armor with an IC2 generator
Once we are fully charged and equipped
We proceed into another expedition
Where our only objective shall be gathering a couple of glowstone dusts
We quickly accomplish the mission and then run back
With that rushed loot
We can finally make a couple of HV capacitors
And thus we can install a railgun in our robotic hand
And of course
We crank it at maximum power
The railgun has two main purposes
One is to be used as a long range weapon
But the most important one
Is that we can use it to fly around by using its kickback
And thus we were able to quickly find a desert
Where we can gather the other missing ingredient for the control circuits, cactus
And with that we can have a solar generator on our helmet
And we can also get night vision goggles
Then an auto-feeder so that we won't have to manage food
And an electrolyzer for when we go diving
But the real cool thing is getting a kinetic generator
This will produce energy when we walk
But it will make walking harder
However, it produces more than the exoskeleton assistant uses
But this is a techpack
So enough fooling around
We shall make a bunch more of the old Thermal Expansion machines
And we shall use these to expand our base
Since the real machines, the GregTech ones, will need more space
And while we wait for the building materials
We can do some more resource gathering
But it looks like it is going to take a while more for the basic processing stuff
So we shall use that time to go gather more ender pearls in the end for some more armor upgrades
And on our way to the end
We found a dungeon
While exploring the dungeon
We found one more fun toy
A portal gun
This is one more memory of great game's
For those of you who don't know
This item allow us to create portals on the walls so that we can easily move around
It can also be used to move around any mob or item
And yes, its best usage was to troll people when playing on multiplayer servers
Anyways, going back to our adventure
Once we managed to find and complete the end portal
We started gathering some ender pearls
But when we had enough and wanted to go back
We found out that the portal gun was not going to bring us away from that nasty place
And thus it was time for the usual long battle with the dragon
Or at least we feared it would have been a long battle
The rail gun is overpowered and in this version the dragon is the vanilla one
Once we took care of having a way back
We can go back and mind our business in pace
And thus we are bringing back some sodalite, some celestite and some tungstate
With the ender pearls we are going to make some force field emitters
Which can be used for a weightless armor that provides more Protection than a diamond one but at cost of energy
And thus we can lift some weight out of our armor
One other cool thing we can do with these things is add a plasma cannon to our hand
Anyways, to fix our portal issues and make our base work properly
We make a chunk loader
And now we can go back to our base from any place
Now that we have secured some materials and a new room
We can move on from the machines that will use Redstone Force and start working on the GregTech ones
This version of GregTech actually works as an IC2 addon
So we have to start with a BatBox and a generator from said mod
We make a line of LV cabling and place a compressor too
And now it is time to do some GregTech stuff
As usual, we start from a bending machine
And if you wonder why I didn't start from the wiremill
It's because it requires plates
Also, apparently, it can be made with machine hulls from any mod
After quickly crafting and placing it
We can start using it and notice that it makes 3 wires from an ingot
Then comes the assembler
Which for the moment we are not going to use
Since the minium stones trades makes the crafting table circuit recipe cheaper than the assembler one
Next we make a centrifuge for cheaper rubber
And to start working our ores, an electrolyzer
However that requires MV power
But since we can tier skip
We rush an HV battery, the MFSU
But now our puny coal generator can barely make the power level of our battery tick up
So we make a couple of Thermal generators
And a setup to pump some lava from the nether
Which we bring to our new generators using a good old tesseract
Which doesn't even require power to work
And thus we should have increased our power generation by a factor of five
Thus we should have enough power to afford making an energy bridge to convert IC2 power into BuildCraft power
And so we can finally have a proper power source for our RF machines
Which are still useful for a handful of tasks
Now we can go back to our first MV machine
The electrolyzer
We shall use that to get stuff like aluminum out of sodalite
But the most important thing we need to electrolyze is bauxite
Which will give us not rutile but straight up titanium dust
And of course, to cook that stuff we need an EBF
Which we swiftly craft
And that machine was a power (hog?) multiblock even back in these days
We can see the structure guideline inside the UI
After crafting and quickly building its structure
We realize that in this version, there is no muffler hatch
So after closing off the top
We see that the light turns green
And we have a heat capacity of 1,020 Kelvin
Which is not enough for smelting titanium
And for some reason
Aluminum here has an even higher working temperature
If we look at the UI
We see two red dots in the structure
That is because we can increase the furnace temperature by adding some lava inside it
So we grab two buckets
Take some lava out of our generators
And proceed into dropping it inside the blast furnace
And thus we reached 1,520 Kelvin
Enough for titanium but not for aluminum
So, let's fire up our electric lava furnace with titanium
After a long cooking time
We got two ingots
Which we turn into plates
And use to make a rock cutter
Which is a power tool that will acquire Silk Touch 3 once fully charged up
We can use that to gently take minerals out of the rock without damaging them
So that we can then throw these inside an industrial grinder to get more dust out of our ores
Going back to our EBF
We would also like to manage to cook aluminum
To increase our heat capacity
We first make some steel
Which we use to make some reinforced casings
Each one will increase the temperature by 20 Kelvin
And we can even mix the blocks
We place them in a familiar way
Until we reach 2,000 Kelvin
However, to smelt late-game materials
We need to reach 3,000
We could rebuild the whole structure with the expensive advanced machine casings
But instead we are going to make a bunch of coils
To make these, we start off by cooking some aluminum
Since we now are able to do so
While the aluminum cook
We grind down some rubies into dust
And then we electrolyze some chromium out of them
Which we shall cook as soon as the aluminum is done
Once everything is ready
We rush to the rolling machine
Where we assemble the new coils
To apply them
We simply click on the controller
And finally we reach the temperature required for Tungsten
But as you probably are thinking
You can't say tungsten EBF without running out of power
So, it is time to increase our power production
The first upgrade we shall do is a gas turbine
So that we can recycle the methane and hydrogen made as by product of various processes
Next, to have some perpetual generation
We make an automated farm with factorization
We are going to use a Sawmill to get the most out of the wood
And we also work the sawdust into charcoal for extra fuel generation
Then we burn all that fuel into a classical RailCraft boiler to make steam
Once it heated up and started producing steam
We feed that into a steam consumer of an energy bridge
Which will then feed power to the farm and send the leftover to our base
This system also makes some sludgy fluid
Which we pipe into a sludgy boiler that will send back to use some extra goodies
However, after some time
We realize that our farm outproduces the boiler consumption
So we increase the size of our boiler
Once this big boy starts producing energy
We realize that we have a surplus production even while using the blast furnace
So we start looking for a good use for that extra power
We shall make a mass fabricator
Which is going to take quite a few crafting steps
And the only thing preventing us from making it is the Lapotron energy orb
Or better, the iridium plate
We are going to need an implosion compressor and also some iridium
I haven't found any iridium ore
And I don't remember if it even spawns in this version
To get it we have two other options
Both of which include platinum
And we can get half a iridium ingot from each sheldonite ore if we work it with mercury in an industrial grinder
Sheldonite is a quite memetic ore found in the end
If we want to gather a proper amount
We should go off to the small floating islands
However, our current way of flying isn't good enough for that
Instead, we shall gather some ender pearls
So that we can craft some thrusters that we can attach to our armor for a proper jetpack flight
Once we have properly attached and configured the jetpack
We can rush back to the end
And finally fly towards the small floating islands
Wherewith the needed materials await us
And now that we have all the required materials
It is time for a crafting sequence
Now that we have managed to craft it
We can place it in the middle of the machine room
And since we want to keep some energy stocked up
We use an EU splitter cable to toggle it on and off
Other than energy
Scraps are mandatory
But we can use any material dust in place
For now we shall use thorium
And that machine uses a lot of power to produce nothing
So, now we can try to find better ways of making power
We start by using the surplus wood from our farm
And with two boiler
We still have excess fuel production and almost make a full HV amp
But that is still nothing
Since that machine can take many amps of IV power
If we want to properly feed it
We are going to need a fusion reactor
However that is a complex machine to make with many steps that require a lot of materials
We do not have AE2 to help us with that
But we have its precursors AE1
We start by making some cabling and some logistic processors
I mean basic processors
Then we make a ME drive with some cells
Instead of having formation and annihilation cores
We have a single conversion matrix
Which we use for our first crafting terminal
Finally, we make some engineering processors
Here called advanced processors to make a controller
Which actually works as an energy acceptor
We start building our AE1 system by dropping down the controller and giving it power
Then we add our disk drive with all the cells we made
And to interact with it
We add our crafting terminal
Now we can drop in all the items we have
Now, to do auto crafting
We need a couple of interfaces and a CPU
And here the CPU is a multiblock with a variable structure
We shall start by making the smallest one
Bigger ones can carry more patterns or craft faster
But this is actually a molecular assembler with embedded interface
To make patterns we need an encoder
And, of course some patterns to encode
As usual, the first patterns we shall prepare are the conversion matrix and the interface
So that we can expand our system
Since these are crafting table recipes
We drop them by the giant molecular assembler
And now time to test out if it works
Looks like it works faster than newer versions too
Now time to encode some assembler recipes
As we should have expected
We can't drag stuff from NEI
So, as in the annoying not too good days
We have to manually craft the first item each time
Now that we have all the inputs and outputs
We can encode the pattern
We place it in an interface on assembler's setup and try to run it
And it almost worked
Just need to click one more button
Now that we have fixed the inputs
We have to wait 2 minutes to test the output
And I can't manage to make the assembler output to the interface
An import bus is kinda of expensive
So we go with a more brutal approach
But for some reason, I couldn't manage to make even that approach work
Also, the way lack of crafting materials and crafting monitoring works isn't as good as in newer versions
So I think we should go back to using chests and math like Chad artisans did in the good old times
Going back to our fusion reactor
We shall start from making the controller
It has many steps
And we should start by gathering some more emeralds
We can get them from this NPC vendor
Which we totally did not kidnap from the isekai village
And to gather some wool to trade with him
We spend a lot of time with some wheat in our hands to lure some sheep into walking miles to get in our herd
However, after all of that work
The vendor now refuses to buy the wool we had to work hard to
So it is time to send him back home using alien technology
Going back to our project
Instead of emeralds
We shall use the olivine we gathered in the end
And once we have all the parts
We can make the two computer cubes
These are not just crafting parts
But can be placed and used in various ways
For example to simulate an IC2 fusion reactor
Which we are not making because it's not as cool as a pink donut
So we take it back
And remember that in this version like IC2, GregTech machines have a chance of breaking when being removed
And while on a mining trip while waiting for the parts to make a new one
We have found the rare iridium ore
Which looks like a leaner
And I'm not sure if a rock cutter can take it
So we shall take it with our bare hands
And here we have one of the many pieces of iridium that we are going to need
We can also use an IC2 miner
But these things pick up more trash than materials
Going back to our little project
We now have the second computer
And we shall move on into working at the first of the 32 coils
This requires some nasty stuff
But I think the worst one is the iridium reflector
This will make each coil cost go up by one iridium plate and eight beryllium cells
Not to mention the 32 dense copper plates
Totalling 4 stacks of copper per coil
To have some extra copper we can centrifuge lava
Which can also be made out of nothing with a lava fabricator
For the moment, we are going to rebuild and repurpose our nether pump and start centrifuging that
While we build up extra copper
We can go back and check how to make beryllium
Apparently, it can only be made by electrolyzing ender pearls or emeralds
I think the most automatable ways has to be using portal mechanics
On a second thought, that is not automatable and neither fun
So we move on to the next step, using a grinder
Once we set it up
We have to trigger some endermen and bait them to teleport into its range
And then we just watch it doing its things from the high of the sky
That setup will also produce some monster essence
Which we can teleport back to our base
Where we may use that essence to power a mob farm to produce even more pearls
Look at how they drop fast
Once we have some to start working with
We can proceed into pulverizing and electrifying these
And thus we finally have the beryllium
We also get some nitrogen and potassium as by product
Which can be used to make gunpowder for the explosives to compress the iridium plates
Finally, we compress a lot of copper
So that we can fill our inventory with neutron reflector that we combine into the iridium neutron reflector
The only thing left to make is the superconductor
Which will need one more iridium plate
So, while our assemblers are working on the energy flow circuits
We head back to the end to mine more sheldonite
While there, we can also gather some sodalite
Which can be electrolyzed to obtain some sodium
And we use that for making sodium-potassium coolant cells
Now that we have everything
We can finish our superconductor
And then complete the first fusion coil
Finally, we can appreciate the crafting process of the fusion control computer without any video speed up
To get started we prepare a donut of dirt
And place the computer as the first final block that touches the ring in the inner side
Now we have to craft a lot of stuff
And we shall start from the coils
To do that, the first step shall be to step on our charge pad
So that we keep our armor charged while being AFK
After being AFK for some time
Our centrifuges managed to make some copper and electrum
Which are fundamental for the coils
Now, the copper will be required for all the neutron reflectors
And the electrum will greatly cut the cost of the circuits
But the main issue is going to be the highly advanced machine block
We need 2 stacks of titanium and 2 of chromium
Titanium could be made by staying AFK to stock up UU-matter
But chromium can only be made by rubies
And that would make us have to dig 7 stacks of them
Which is not going to happen
The IC2 mine doesn't seem to work properly
So we shall take its drill and upgrade it to a quarry
And we can get some extra diamonds by compressing all the junk that came out of the sludge of our farm
On diamond you can't grow flowers
But you can use sludge to make diamonds that can craft a quarry that will gather every useful resource you could possibly need
We place it with some tesseract to manage its input and outputs
Then we can watch its robot build the structure
Once the frame is complete
The head will start running with all the power of about one blast furnace
On the other side of the tesseract
We are managing the output in the worst possible way
Since I can't find any better compatible pipe
After some time
We have managed to fill one super chest of cobblestone
And we can see about what we are going to get from our quarry
So, we can move our tesseract to a better sorting facility
We shall stock inside some barrels all of the garbage from decorative mods that can cause visual glitches and lag
While we keep the good stuff inside this chest
Then, since we are going to have a lot of extra quartz
We can use that to make input buses and other AE1 stuff to automate the processing
And we shall invest two coils worth of machine hulls in a quantum chest to see how much cobblestone we dig
So, time to start using all of that goodies
We shall also improve our workshop to be more automatic
However, it looks like back in the day
Artisans used to make good stuff by hand
And not with ugly automated setups
You can tell by the lack of vanilla hoppers and how hard it is to get stuff out of chests and machines
And after many tries
I gave up upon trying to get plates out of a bending machine
It have has something that looks like the newer auto output function
But I'm too clumsy to make it work
Anyways, we make a second grinder
And we wall share it with the older one
And stock it up with some water using the worst pipes we could find
Next we also make an electrolyzer
And now we make AE1 craft some input and export buses
Automating Thermal expansion is rather easy
But these old rusty GregTech machines require us to find the correct side for each input
And with that we have automated almost everything like a good (virgin?) engineer should do
The only problematic thing left to manage is Iridium
The only way I know of getting it in good amounts is with UU matter
However, we managed to make only 3 pieces since when we built the matter fabricator
So, maybe we could do a fusion reactor for the moment
Or we could make one ultimate solar panel
Which will give a longer use to the uranium we aren't using
Or maybe not
Since that requires half fusion reactor worth of iridium
Now a vacuum reactor would make quite some power
However, the vacuum freezer would use all that power to cool down the coolant cells
So we have to move on to something more efficient
And there we have a quick and dirty plutonium reactor
Which makes about as much power as two railcraft boilers
We won't use the quad cells because these take too much copper
And once our quarry runs out
We make one more so that it won't be alone in his next location
Double the quarry
Double the fun
And now time to AFK while we stock up resources
Once we have enough
We can start improving our base with the following automation sequence
Once we complete the donut
We add two input material injectors
One material injector and four energy injectors
Which have the same location of the GTNH fusion reactors
Next, we connect the power and we wait for the reactor internal buffer to charge up
With our current production, that will take about a quarter of an hour
While we wait
Let's prepare the fuel
We start by electrolyzing some hydrogen out of water
Next we centrifuge some deuterium out of that
Finally, we make some tritium out of deuterium
Now, when we will fuse deuterium and tritium
We are going to get some helium plasma
Which, to be used, requires a plasma generator
That machine contains some tungsten steel
Which, as the tooltip says, has to be vacuum hardened
So, while our tungsten steel is cooking
We shall work on a vacuum freezer
And as expected, that is a multiblock machine
But it's always the same machine hulls
And we quickly complete it
Meanwhile, our fusion reactor reached one quarter of the charge
But that might be the maximum of our reactor
Since we only have four of the 16 maximum energy injectors
So let's try giving it some fuel and let's see if it works
The lights did not turn on
But we lost all of our stored energy
But it looks like we managed to get one cell of plasma
To keep a sustained fusion
We craft one more energy injector
And attach it to the coils
After buffering up enough power again
We drop in the fuel
And this time the lights turned on
And we are producing a constant flux of helium plasma
Other than the hot plasma
We also have hot tungsten steel
And only one of the two shall go inside the vacuum freezer
And thus we have our plasma generator
Which we shall place right next to the matter fabricator
Finally, we feed it some plasma
So that we can finally have a proper UU matter production
Our matter fabricator is indeed receiving so much power that it can't even work that fast
And its energy buffer is filling up
And as you probably noticed
That's not just the power of one plasma generator
It's also the power of the new generators on the wall
The only thing left to do is to show off our cobblestone collection in our AE1 system
So we make a storage bus
And connect it to the quantum Chest
员工们好
今天我们要再玩一个又老又好的整合包 FTB Ultimate
这也是我第一次遇到 GregTech 这个 mod 的整合包
总之 我们快速新建一个新世界
我们出生在一个村庄附近 不过这个村庄似乎没有任何战利品箱
快速瞄了一眼之后
我们开始做原版的生存流程
也就是速速做一张床然后收集一些材料
既然我们有了床和一些食物
可以去采集一些矿物了
这些应该足够让我们的基地启动了
我们要做的第一件事是搞点建筑材料
我们打算用经典可靠的石砖来建造基地
经过一番工作之后
这就是我们的新基地了 顶上有一扇漂亮的天窗
现在我们可以开始用老版本的粉碎机来处理矿物了
这是在 Forge Energy （FE）单位出现之前的版本
我们曾经用的是 Minecraft Joules（MJ）
好 在继续建设我们的工厂之前
我们先去搞点像样的工具
比如动力装甲
这个版本的装甲看起来好挫
我们刚做这个装甲出来的时候
它只会让我们外观看上去不一样而已
要让它真正有用
我们需要一个动力装甲改装台
它需要一颗绿宝石 而我们挖矿的时候并没有找到
不过幸运的是 这个版本有村民交易
那个村民的出价很不错
我们从公会大厅接下了这个任务
然后迅速完成它
这样我们就有了改装台来调整我们的装甲
在里面可以看到装甲已装备的模块
我们可以添加、移除或编辑它们
我们首先想要的是加一些装甲板 这样就能提供一定的防护
我们快速合成了升级所需的材料
然后安装到我们的装甲上
接下来 我们可以选择装甲板有多厚
越厚 我们获得的护甲就越多
但我们也需要承担更多的重量
既然我们想保护做到位
我们在装甲的每一件上都装了最厚的那一档
于是我们就拥有了一件不损坏 和钻石甲一样好但用的只是铁做成的装甲
问题是它很重
为了解决这个问题
我们可以在护腿上安装一些增强模块来帮助我们在负重状态下行走
同样 我们可以调整这些增强模块的功率大小和它们帮助我们行走的方式
然而 这些都需要电力
所以我们还必须安装电池
这会让我们的重量进一步增加
当然 我们还需要一些发电机来给电池充电
然而 所有可以嵌入装甲的发电机都需要控制电路
而控制电路需要荧石
在去下界之前
我们先合成一个电动工具
其他所有工具都可以不用了
释放大量快捷栏空间
这个机械臂非常万能
比如作为基本的挖矿工具
为了挖掘黑曜石
我们可以用一些钻石来升级它
而且我们可能需要把镐子功能超频到最大来完成这个任务
这样我们就可以用我们的机器手来挖掘黑曜石了
在进入下界之前 我们还应该搞一些更酷的功能
比如轨道炮
或者我们可以晚点再做
目前先搞一个近战助手应该就够了
然后我们用 IC2 发电机给装甲充满电
一旦我们充满电并装备齐全
我们开始另一趟远征
这趟的唯一目标是收集一些荧石粉
我们迅速完成任务然后回家
带着这些匆忙收集的战利品
我们终于可以做几个高压电容器了
这样我们就可以在机械手上安装轨道炮了
当然
我们把它按到最大功率
轨道炮有两个主要用途
一个是作为远程武器使用
但最重要的那个
是我们可以利用它的后坐力飞来飞去
于是我们能很快就找到一片沙漠
在那里我们可以获得控制电路所需缺少的另一种材料——仙人掌
有了它 我们就可以在头盔上装一个太阳能发电机了
我们还可以搞到夜视镜
然后是自动喂食器 这样我们就不用管食物了
还有我们潜水时用的电解器
但真正夯的是搞一个动能发电机
这个模块会在我们走路的时候产生能量
但它会让行走变得更困难
然而 它产生的能量比外骨骼辅助消耗的还要多
但这是个科技整合包
所以别再摸鱼了
我们得多做一些老版本的热力膨胀机器
然后用它们来扩建我们的基地
因为 GregTech 的那些真正的机器需要更多空间
在我们等待建筑材料的时候
我们可以再多收集一些资源
不过看起来基础处理工序还需要花不少时间
所以我们就利用这段时间去末地多收集一些末影珍珠 用来做更多装甲升级
在去末地的路上
我们发现了一个地牢
在探索地牢的时候
我们找到了另一个有趣的玩具
一把传送枪
这是又一个伟大游戏的美好回忆
如果你不知这个枪什么用的话
这个物品可以让我们在墙上创建传送门 这样我们就能轻松地传送
它还可以用来移动任何生物或物品
没错 它最夯的用法是在多人服务器上整蛊别人
不管怎样 回到我们的冒险
等我们找到并搭建好了末地传送门
我们开始收集一些末影珍珠
但当我们收集够了想要回去的时候
我们发现传送枪并不能把我们带离那个糟糕的地方
于是就又到了和龙进行持久战的时候了
或者说至少我们以为是一场持久恶战
这个版本轨道炮实在太强了 而且这个版本的龙是原版的
等我们搞定了回家的路
就可以回去安心忙我们的事了
于是我们带回了一些方钠石、天青石以及一些钨酸锂
我们用末影珍珠做一些力场发射器
它可以用来做没有重量的装甲 护甲比钻石甲更高 但消耗能量
这样我们就能让装甲减重了
这些东西还能做的另一个很夯的事是在手上加一门等离子炮
不管怎样 为了解决传送门的问题并让基地正常运行
我们做了一个区块加载器
现在我们就可以从任何地方回到基地了
现在我们弄到了一些材料和新房间
我们可以从那些使用 Redstone Force （RF）的机器中毕业 开始做 GregTech 的机器了
这个版本的 GregTech 实际上是 IC2 的一个附属 mod 的
所以我们得先做一个低压存电箱和一个那个 mod 的发电机
我们铺了一条低压线缆 又放压缩机
现在是时候做点 GregTech 的东西了
像往常一样 我们从卷板机开始
如果你好奇为什么我不从线材轧机开始
是因为线材轧机配方需要板
另外 很显然 它可以用任何 mod 的机器外壳来制作
快速合成并放下之后
我们开始使用它 发现一个锭可以做出 3 根导线
然后轮到了组装机
目前我们暂且不用它
因为用贤者之石交易工作台电路比用组装机做更便宜
接下来我们做一个离心机 用来搞便宜的橡胶
然后要开始处理矿石了 做一个电解机
然而这需要 MV 电力
不过既然我们可以跳级
我们直接速做了一个高压电池——MFSU
但现在我们那可怜的燃煤发电机几乎填不上电池的电量
所以我们做了几个地热发电机
还有一个从下界抽岩浆的装置
我们用一个又老又好的超立方体把它输送到新发电机那里
它甚至不需要电力就能工作
这样我们的发电量应该提升了五倍
这样我们应该有足够的电力来做一座能量转换器 把 IC2 电力转换成 BC 电力
这样我们就终于能给我们的 RF 机器提供像样的电源了
它们在少部分任务里仍然有用
现在我们回到第一台中压机器
电解机
我们会用它获得一些矿物 比如从方钠石中提取铝
但我们需要电解的最重要的东西是铝土矿
它电解出的不是金红石 而是直接给钛粉
当然 要烧这些东西我们需要一台电高炉
我们速合成出来
这台机器即使在当时也已经是一个耗电大户的多方块结构了
我们可以在 UI 里面看到结构指南
合成并速搭好结构之后
我们意识到这个版本里没有消声仓
所以在封上顶部之后
我们看到指示灯变绿了
我们有了 1020K 的热容量
这还不足以熔炼钛
而且不知为什么
这个版本里铝的工作温度更高
如果看一下界面
我们看到结构中有两个红点
那是因为我们可以往里面加岩浆来提高炉温
所以我们拿两桶
从我们的发电机里取出一些岩浆
然后把它倒进高炉里
于是我们达到了 1520K
足够烧钛但不够烧铝
那么 让我们把电高炉开起来 烧钛
经过了漫长的烧制时间之后
我们得到了两个锭
把它们做成板
然后用来做一个岩石切割机
这是一个电动工具 充满电后能获得精准采集 III
我们可以用它来温柔地把矿石从岩石里取出来 不损坏它们
这样我们就可以把它们扔进工业研磨机里 从矿石中获得更多的粉
回到我们的电高炉
我们还想烧铝
为了提升热容量
我们先做一些钢
用它们来做一些强化外壳
每个强化外壳能提升 20K 的温度
而且我们还可以混着用
我们用一种熟悉的方式摆放它们
直到我们达到 2000K
然而 要熔炼后期材料
我们需要达到 3000K
我们可以用昂贵的进阶机器外壳重建整个结构
但反过来 我们打算做一堆线圈
要开始做线圈 我们先烧一些铝
因为我们现在能烧了
在铝烧制的过程中
我们把一些红宝石磨成粉
然后从里面电解出铬
铝一烧完我们就开始烧它
一切都准备就绪之后
我们冲到辊压机那里
在那里我们把新线圈组装起来
要安装它们
我们只需要点一下控制器
终于我们达到了烧钨所需的温度
但正如你可能在想的那样
你不可能用电高炉烧钨而不把电用完
所以 是时候提高我们的发电量了
我们要做的第一个升级是燃气涡轮
这样我们就可以回收各种工序产生的副产：甲烷和氢气
接下来 为了保持持续的发电
我们用因式分解做了一个自动化农场
我们打算用锯木机来最大化木材的产出
我们还把锯末加工成木炭 以产生更多燃料
然后我们把这些燃料全部烧进一台经典的 RC 锅炉来产生蒸汽
等它加热并开始产生蒸汽之后
我们把蒸汽送进能量转换器的蒸汽消耗器
然后它就会向农场供电并把其他电送回基地
这个系统还会产生一些污泥流体
我们把它用管道送进一个污泥锅炉 它会给我们一些额外的电量
然而 过了一段时间之后
我们发现农场产量超出了锅炉的消耗
于是我们加大了锅炉的尺寸
等这个大家伙开始产能之后
我们发现即使在用着高炉的情况下仍然有富余产量
于是我们开始找这些多余电力的好用途
我们将做一个物质制造机
这需要相当多的合成步骤
而唯一阻碍我们做出它的东西就是兰博顿能量球
或者更准确地说 铱板
我们需要一台聚爆压缩机和一些铱
我还没有找到任何铱矿石
而且我不记得铱矿石是否在这个版本中生成
为了得到它 我们还有另外两种方案
两种方案都和铂有关
如果我们在工业研磨机中使用汞来处理谢尔顿矿石 每个可以得到半个铱锭
谢尔顿矿可以在末地找到 一种名字很有梗的矿石
如果我们想收集到足够的数量
我们应该去那些小浮岛
然而 我们目前的飞行方式还不方便
另一种方法是 我们先收集一些末影珍珠
这样我们就可以制作一些推进器 安装到装甲上 实现真正的喷气背包飞行
等我们把喷气背包安装好并正确配置之后
我们可以冲回末地
终于可以飞向那些小浮岛了
那里有我们需要的材料在等着我们
现在我们有了所有需要的材料
是时候来一段手搓纯享版了
既然我们把它合成了出来
我们可以把它放在工作间正中央
既然我们想储存一些能量
我们用 EU 分线线缆来控制开关
除了能量之外
废料是强制性的
不过我们可以用别的材料粉末来替代
现在我们先用钍
既然这台机器消耗巨量电力却什么也不产出
那么现在我们可以尝试找更好的发电方式
我们从利用农场多产出的木材开始
用上了两个锅炉
我们仍然燃料产量有余 产出几乎到 HV 的 1A
但这还不够
因为那台机器可以吃进好 IV 的好几 A
如果我们想满足它的能源需求
我们需要一个聚变反应堆
然而那是一台制造过程很复杂、步骤很多、需要大量材料的机器
我们没有 AE2 来帮我们
但我们有它的前身 AE1
我们先做一些线缆和一些物流处理器
我是说基础处理器
然后我们做一个 ME 驱动器 还有一些存储元件
AE1 里没有成形核心和破坏核心
取而代之的是一个转换矩阵
我们用它来制作第一个合成终端
最后 我们做一些工程处理器
在这里叫做进阶处理器 用来做一个控制器
它的实际功能是能量接收器
我们开始搭建 AE1 系统 放置控制器方块并给它通电
然后我们加上磁盘驱动器以及我们做好的所有存储元件
要与之交互的话
我们加上合成终端
现在我们可以把所有物品都丢进去了
现在 要做自动合成
我们需要几个接口和一个 CPU
在这里 CPU 是一个可变尺寸的多方块结构
我们从做最小的结构那个开始
更大的可以容纳更多样板或者合成得更快
但这其实是一个有界面的分子装配室
要做样板的话 我们需要一个编码器
当然 还有一些需要编码的空白样板
像往常一样 我们首先准备的样板是转换矩阵和接口
这样我们就可以扩展我们的系统
由于这些是工作台配方
我们把它们放在巨大的分子装配室里
现在是时候测试一下它是否正常工作了
看起来它比新版本合成得还要快
现在是时候编码一些组装机配方了
正如我们所料
我们不能从 NEI 拖拽物品
所以 一如当年那些又烦又不好的日子
我们每次都必须手动合成第一个物品
现在我们有了所有的输入和输出
我们可以编码样板了
我们把它放在组装机配置的接口上 并尝试运行
它差点就成功了
只需要点一个按钮就能修复
现在我们修好了输入的问题
我们必须每次等两分钟来测试输出
而且我不能让组装机正确输出回接口
输入总线有点贵
所以我们采取了一个更暴力的做法
但不知为何 我连那个方法也没能让它正常输出
另外 缺少合成材料和合成监控这一点 做得也不如后来的版本好
所以我觉得我们应该回到用箱子和手动算材料的方式 像老资历以前那样又老又好地手搓
回到我们的聚变反应堆
我们从制作控制器开始
合成步骤很多
我们应该从多收集一些绿宝石开始
我们可以从这个交易 NPC 那里获得
当然我们绝对没有从异世界村庄绑他回来
为了收集羊毛来跟他交易
我们花了很多时间 拿着小麦勾引一些羊走很远的路来加入我们的羊群
然而 做完这么多工作之后
这个 NPC 现在拒绝购买我们辛辛苦苦弄来的羊毛
所以是时候用外星科技送他回家了
回到我们的目标上
不用绿宝石了
我们用之前在末地收集到的橄榄石代替
等我们有了所有合成材料之后
我们可以做出两个计算机立方体
这些不仅仅是合成材料
还可以放置下来 有不少功能
例如模拟一个 IC2 聚变反应堆
我们不打算做那个 因为它没有粉色甜甜圈那么有逼格
所以我们把它取回来
然后想起来了 和 IC2 一样 这个版本里 GregTech 机器在拆除时有几率损坏
在挖矿的过程中 一边等零件做一个新的
我们找到了罕见的铱矿石
它似乎在地层里相当贫瘠
我也不确定岩石切割机能不能挖得动
所以我们徒手把它挖下来
这就是我们需要的众多铱中的一份
我们也可以使用 IC2 矿机
但这些挖出来的垃圾比材料还多
回到我们的小目标上
现在我们有了第二台计算机
我们要开始动手做 32 个线圈中的第一个了
这需要一些相当恶心的材料
但我觉得最恶心的是铱反射板
这导致每个线圈都会消耗一个铱板和八个铍单元
更不用提 32 个致密铜板了
每个线圈总计要 4 组铜
要得到额外的铜 我们可以离心岩浆
岩浆可以用岩浆制造机凭空做出来
目前 我们先重构并改造下界的抽岩浆系统并且开始离心岩浆
在我们积攒额外铜的同时
我们可以回去查查怎么做铍
显然 只能通过电解末影珍珠或绿宝石来得到
我觉得最可自动化的方式应该是用传送门机制
再一想 这自动化不了 也不好玩
于是我们进入下一步 用研磨机
设置好之后
我们需要激怒一些末影人 勾引它们传送到机器的范围内
然后我们就从高空的视角看着它工作
这个装置还会产出一些怪物精华
我们可以把它传送回基地
在那里我们可以用精华来驱动一个刷怪塔以产生更多的珍珠
看它们掉得有多快
有了一些可以开始加工的材料之后
我们把它们打粉并电解
于是我们终于有了铍
我们还得到了一些氮和钾作为副产品
它们可以用来制造火药 做爆炸物来压缩铱板
最后 我们压缩了大量铜
这样我们就能用中子反射板填满背包 再做成铱中子反射板
唯一剩下的就是超导体了
它还需要一个铱板
所以 趁我们的组装机在工作能量流电路的时候
我们回到末地去挖更多谢尔顿矿
在末地 我们还可以收集一些方钠石
可以通过电解获得钠
我们用它们来做钠钾冷却剂单元
现在我们材料都齐了
我们可以做出超导体了
然后做出第一个聚变线圈
终于 我们可以欣赏聚变控制计算机的合成过程 不用任何视频变速
一开始我们先准备一个泥土甜甜圈
然后把计算机作为第一个接触环内侧的最终方块放下去
接下来我们要合成大量材料
我们从线圈开始
要做到这一点 第一步是踩在我们的充电板上
这样我们挂机的时候装甲可以保持充电
挂机了一段时间之后
我们的离心机产出了一些铜和琥珀金
这些都是线圈的基础材料
铜是所有中子反射板都需要的
而琥珀金将大大降低电路的成本
但主要的问题将是超进阶机器方块
我们需要两组的钛和两组的铬
钛可以通过挂机囤积 UU 物质来做
但铬只能用红宝石来做
那我们就得挖 7 组红宝石
这不太现实
那个 IC2 矿机似乎不能正常工作
所以我们将把它的钻头升级为采石场
而且我们可以通过压缩我们农场污泥里产出的所有垃圾来获得额外的钻石
在钻石上面你种不了花
但是你可以用污泥来制造钻石 再用钻石来合成采石场 它会挖到你所有需要的资源
我们放下它再加上一些超立方体来管理它的输入输出
然后我们就能欣赏它的机器人搭建结构
框架完成之后
切割头就会开始运行 耗电量大约相当于一台高炉
在超立方体的另一端
我们在以最坏的方式管理输出
因为我找不到任何更好的 能和超立方体兼容的管道
过了一段时间
我们已经填满了一个超级圆石箱子
我们可以看看从采石场中能获得什么
那么 我们可以把超立方体接上一个更好的分类装置
我们会把装饰 mod 产生的所有垃圾存进桶里 那些东西会导致渲染问题和卡顿
好东西留在这个箱子里
然后 既然我们会有大量的多余石英
我们可以用它来做输入总线和其他 AE1 的东西来自动化处理
我们将投入相当于两个线圈份量的机器外壳去做一个量子箱 来看看我们到底挖了多少圆石
那么 是时候开始使用所有这些好东西了
我们还要改进我们的车间使其更自动化
不过 看起来在当年
老资历们都是手工搓出好东西的
而不是用丑陋的自动化装置
从原版漏斗的缺失以及把东西从箱子和机器中取出来有多难就能看出来
试了很多次之后
我放弃了从卷板机里取出板的尝试
它上面有个东西看起来像新版自动输出的功能
但我手太笨了 死活搞不定
不管怎样 我们做了第二台研磨机
和旧的那台共用结构方块
然后用我们能找到的最烂的管道给它加满水
接下来我们还做了一台电解机
现在我们让 AE1 合成一些输入总线和输出总线
自动化热力膨胀的机器相当容易
但这些老旧生锈的 GregTech 机器要求我们为每个输入找到正确的面
就这样我们几乎自动化了一切 像一个优秀的楚南工程师应该做的那样
唯一剩下的麻烦就是铱了
我知道的唯一能大量获取的方式就是 UU 物质
然而 自从我们建成物质制造机以来只做出了 3 个
所以 或许我们可以先做一个聚变反应堆
或者我们可以做一个终极太阳能板
这样就能让用不上的铀有更长期的用途
可能不做也好
因为那需要半个聚变反应堆份量的铱
真空反应堆倒是能发不少电
然而 真空冷冻机会用掉所有那些电力去冷却冷却剂单元
所以我们必须选择更高效的方案
于是我们就有了一个简易粗糙的钚反应堆
发电大约相当于两台 RC 锅炉
我们不会用四联燃料棒 因为那太耗铜了
等我们的采石场挖完之后
我们再做一个 这样它在下一个工地就不会孤单了
双倍的采石场
双倍的快乐
现在是时候挂机囤积资源了
等我们有了足够的量
我们就可以通过以下自动化序列开始改进我们的基地了
甜甜圈刚完成
我们就加上两个输入材料注射器
一个材料输出器和四个能量注射器
位置和 GTNH 聚变反应堆的一样
接下来 接上电源等待反应堆内部缓冲充能
以我们目前的发电量 大概需要一刻钟
等待期间
我们准备一下燃料
我们从电解水获得氢开始
接下来离心分离出一些氘
最后 用氘做出一些氚
当我们聚变氘和氚的时候
我们会得到一些氦等离子体
要使用它 需要一台等离子发电机
那台机器包括一些钨钢材料
正如 Tooltip 所说的 钨钢必须进行真空硬化
所以在钨钢烧制的期间
我们要做一台真空冷冻机
如预期的那样 这是一台多方块机器
但用的还是同样的机器外壳
我们很快就建好了
与此同时 我们的聚变反应堆充到了四分之一的电量
但这可能就是反应堆的上限了
因为能量注射器上限是 16 个 我们只有 4 个
那么试试给它喂点燃料看看它能不能工作
灯没有亮
但我们损失了所有储存的能量
不过看起来我们设法得到了一单元等离子体
为了保持持续聚变
我们再多做一个能量注射器
并把它装到线圈上
在再次缓冲足够能量之后
我们丢进燃料
这次灯亮了
我们正在持续产生氦等离子体流
除了热等离子体
我们也有热钨钢
一半热钨钢应该放进真空冷冻机
这样我们就有了等离子发电机
我们把它放在物质制造机旁边
最后 喂它一些等离子体
这样我们终于能有一个像样的 UU 物质生产了
我们的物质制造机确实接收了太多能量 以至于它都来不及工作那么快
它的能量缓冲正在被充满
而且 你大概也注意到了
这不仅仅是一台等离子发电机的功率
其实 还包括墙上那些新发电机的功率
唯一剩下要做的事就是 在我们的 AE1 系统中展示一下我们的圆石收藏
所以我们做了一个存储总线
然后把它连接到量子箱子